binarytides.com 2018-03-07

# Privacy Policy – BinaryTides

#### Overview

This privacy policy sets out the privacy policies and practices for Binarytides with respect to the collection, use, and disclosure of user/visitor information (personal or not) by Binarytides. This Privacy Policy applies to information collected from you by Binarytides via this website binarytides.com. The security of your data is of utmost importance to Binarytides. We value you as a site visitor and we are committed to maintaining your privacy and securing any information you may provide through our site.

#### Definitions

As used in this Privacy Policy, "Binarytides" or binarytides or "this site" or "The site" refers to the website binarytides.com

#### Accept this prior to using this site

By visiting this site, viewing our content, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy.

#### Information Collection

**Information collected automatically**

Binarytides may automatically (without the user being aware or notified) receive/log/collect certain types of information when you visit or interact with this site, services, mobile applications or other products.

The collected information includes but may not be limited to

  * Browser Information
  * Operating System Information
  * Mobile Device Information (e.g., device identifier, mobile operating system, etc.)
  * IP Address
  * Internet Service Provider
  * Content Viewed
  * Geographic Location
  * Connection Speed
  * Time of Visit
  * Referring Site, Application, or Service
  * Registration Time

**Comments, Public Posts, sharing on third party websites**

Binarytides encourages active participation by users, through comments on this site and other methods like sharing on social websites etc. However, please be aware that if you voluntarily disclose Information, personal or otherwise, on Binarytides, that Information can be viewed, collected and used by others, including other users, search engines, advertisers, third party applications developers, and anyone with access to Binarytides. Binarytides has no control over the use, collection or disclosure of any Information that you post publicly on Binarytides. 

Binarytides may also use a third party comment system (like Disqus, Facebook etc) on this site, which may require the user to register with those third party site. Such third party sites may place "cookie" on the user's browser.

**Mailing Lists & Service Emails**

This site may be running a mailing list, in order to provide subscribers with relevant information like new articles, weekly or daily round-ups, for example. In order to sign up to receive regular emails from this site's mailing list, users must submit information including a valid email address and demographic information such as location and interests. 

This information will be used in aggregate form only in order to assess general user interest in various internal and third party products and services, and your personal and contact information will not be passed to any other organization. Users who choose to sign up for a mailing list will receive regular emails from the site. This site may from time to time track user email usage in a continued effort to improve our services. Most of the time, these will be content from the site, but we may occasionally send out an email from a third party sponsor. This will be infrequent, and does not represent an endorsement by the Site of any products advertised therein. It will clearly be marked as advertising.

If you do not wish to receive emails from third party advertisers, please do not sign up for the mailing list.

**Use of cookies**

A "cookie" is a small data text file that is placed in your browser and allows this website to recognize you each time you visit this site. A cookie can be used to track the behavior of a user on a particular domain/site.

Binarytides may use cookies to provide users with a better experience when using this site.

Cookies may/will also be used by 3rd party content providers such as

  * Newsfeeds
  * Advertisers like Google Adsense
  * Social sharing sites like twitter, facebook, google, linkedin
  * Comment management services like Disqus
  * Visitor analytics services like Google Analytics

Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information, and this site does not use cookies to collect any personal information.

**Control your privacy**

If you do not want this site to place and use cookies on your computer, you should set your browser preferences to refuse cookies before accessing this site. Binarytides is not responsible for any failure by you or your browser to block cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of this site that depend on cookies.

#### Third party advertisements on this site

This site uses third party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit this site. For example Google Adsense. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a **cookie** or third party web beacon to collect this information. 

To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Use of cookies by third party advertisements**

Some of our third party advertising partners may distribute cookies to users through the advertisements that are displayed/delivered on this site.

Binarytides or the site does not control and **is not responsible** for the use of cookies by its third party partners or advertisers.

Binarytides holds no responsibility for the technologies, tools or practices of the advertisers that provide advertising and related services on this site. This Privacy Policy does not cover any collection, use or disclosure of information by advertisers who provide advertising and related services on Binarytides. These advertisers' information gathering practices, including their policies regarding the use of cookies and other tracking technologies, are governed entirely by their own privacy policies, not this one.

**About Google Adsense program**

Any advertisements served by Google Inc. (Google Adsense Program), and affiliated companies may be using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. Learn how to [opt out of Google's cookie usage](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/). Any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google's own privacy policies.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Third Party and Online Behavioral Advertising opt out - Please visit this link to opt-out of cookies from over 50+ major third party behavioral advertising providers <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

#### About analytics services

Binarytides uses third party analytics providers and products (for example Google Analytics) to obtain, compile and analyze information (that may include **Personally Identifying Information** ) about how users are using and interacting with this site. Binarytides may provide this information (including Personally Identifying Information) to these analytics providers for the purpose of obtaining statistics and other information about how users are using and interacting with this site. These analytics providers may use tracking techniques other than http cookies to recognize your computer or device and/or to collect or compile this information. These techniques may be used directly on this site. Binarytides has **no responsibility** for the technologies, tools or practices of the third parties that providing analytics products and services to Binarytides. 

Please also keep in mind that your web browser may not permit you to block the use of these techniques, and that browser settings that block conventional cookies may have no effect on such techniques.

#### External Links

The site contain links to other sites. Please be aware that the Site is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Site

#### Credit card details

This site will never ask for Credit Card details and request that you do not enter it on any of the forms on this site.

#### Remember The Risks Whenever You Use The Internet

While we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to this site and you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. In addition other Internet sites or services that may be accessible through binarytides.com have separate data and privacy practices independent of us, and therefore we disclaim any responsibility or liability for their policies or actions.

#### Notification of Changes

Whenever this site changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy page, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

#### How to Contact Us

BinaryTides welcomes any questions or comments you may have regarding this **Privacy Policy** or its implementation. Any such questions or comments should be submitted via email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7b1912151a09020f121f1e083b1c161a121755181416). We will undertake reasonable efforts to resolve or address your concern.

#### Effective Date of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of Dec 7, 2013.

Last Updated On : 8th February 2016
